Josiah Willard Gibbs Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Josiah Willard Gibbs (1839-1903) Correspondence, 1876-1915; Series I; 1.04; (3 boxes)
  - Letters to Gibbs
    - Vieweg, F. und sohn - Copy of an autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs., 1902 July 7 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Waals, Johannes Diderik van der (1837-1923) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs. Amsterdam., 1898? June 20 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Wald, Frantivek (1861-1930) - 2 autograph letters, signed, to [Josiah Willard Gibbs]. Kladno, Bohmen., 1895 January 18 and December 7 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Young, Charles Augustus (1834-1908) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs. Princeton., 1884 March 20 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Collected correspondence and other papers
      - Correspondence concerning proposed German translation of "Statistical Mechanics" (1902) (Box 3, Folder 124)
      - Correspondence between Josiah Willard Gibbs and Longmans, Green & Co. concerning the reprint of Gibbs' thermodynamics papers, including contract., 1903 (Box 3, Folder 125)
        The execution of the contract was interrupted by Gibbs' death, 1903 April 28. See also next folder.
      - Final contract for "Scientific papers" and correspondence regarding the contract between Addison Van Name and Longmans, Green & Co., 1903-1906 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Notes on Scientific Correspondence, 1903-1952 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Mailing Lists (recipients of Gibbs' published papers), 1876-1886 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Miscellaneous notes by Josiah Willard Gibbs., 1888 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Reviews of "Velocity of light in air..." and "Theoretische optik" by Josiah Willard Gibbs., [1885?] (Box 3, Folder 130)
- Notebooks and Scientific Papers, 1855-1903; Series II; 5.09; (12 boxes)
  Arranged in no particular order.
  - "On the Form of the Teeth of Wheels in Spur Gearing" - bound manuscript., 1863 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    Bound in green cloth with gold lettering on spine: "Josiah Willard Gibbs, PH.D. Thesis, Yale College, 1863".
  - Notes on electromagnetic theories of Ampere and Grassman, [1870s] (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - "Method of Computing an Orbit from Three Observations" - manuscript notebook of observations, calculations, etc., undated (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Varia - bound volume containing the manuscripts of Gibbs' solutions to the prize problems of 1855, 1856, and 1857, and a paper on "Unit of Length, etc." read before the Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1866 March 21., 1855-1866 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Gift of Miss Theodora Van Name, 1925
    Bound in green cloth, with gold lettering on spine: "Josiah Willard Gibbs, Varia".
  - Electricity - manuscript notebook. Berlin., 1867 October (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Electricity - manuscript notebook., undated (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Electricity - manuscript notebook., undated (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Turbine - autograph manuscript., 1866 (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - Units and the Fundamental Equation of Theoretical Mechanics - autograph manuscript draft., undated (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - Notes on Carmichael's calculus operation - autograph manuscript., undated (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - Bibliography of Boltzmann on thermodynamics and statistical mechanics - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - Spherical Harmonies - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - Newton: autograph manuscript notes and newspaper clippings relating to Professor Hubert Anson Newton., undated (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - Draft of a letter to Nature and other autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - Thermodynamics Lecture Notes - autograph manuscript notes, 1891-1900 (Box 5, Folder 145)
  - Thermodynamics Lecture Notes - manuscript notebook of notes taken by a student., 1894-1895 (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - Railroad Car Brakes - autograph manuscript of the nature and object of the brake; correspondence with Munn & Co.; and U.S. Patent No. 53,971, with drawings., 1865-1886 (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - Steam Engine Governor - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - On the Values of Potentials in Liquids for Substances Which Form but a Small Part of the Whole Mass - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - Electrolysis and Latent Differences - autograph manuscript notes., 1900, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 150)
  - Electrolysis and Solubilities - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 6, Folder 151)
    Includes four of Gibbs' original folders, labelled as follows: Electrolysis (Bibliography); Electrolysis and solubilities; Solubilities and electrolysis; Similarity in thermodynamics.
  - Verification of E. H. S. Equations, Van der Waals' Equations - autograph manuscript notes., 1884; 2 (Box 6, Folder 152-153)
  - Multiple Algebra: Lecture notes - autograph manuscript notes., 1884-1885, 1889-1891, 1893-1894, 1901-1902 (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - Multiple Algebra: Curvature, Quaternations, Applications to Ellipsoids - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 6, Folder 155)
  - Multiple Algebra: Ausdehnungs-Lehre and Multiple Algebra, Tait's Quaternations, Quaternations and the Ausdehnungslehre, Notes for an A. A. A. S. address - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 6, Folder 156)
    Includes 2 autograph letters, signed, from E. H. Moore on multiple algebra subjects while Moore was studying with Kronecker in Berlin, 1885 December 21, 1886 July 23.
  - Multiple Algebra Studies: Peircian analysis, Salmon's higher algebra, Freeman's problem, Extracanon, etc. - autograph manuscript notes., undated; 2 (Box 6, Folder 157-158)
  - Orbits - survey of Gibbs' papers on Orbits, undated (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - Orbits: Geometry of Ellipsoid - autograph manuscript notes., 1884-1885 (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - Orbits - autograph manuscript notes., 1889-1890 (Box 7, Folder 161)
  - Orbits - autograph manuscript notes., 1892-1893 (Box 7, Folder 162)
  - Orbits: Elliptic Motion - autograph manuscript notes., 1884 (Box 7, Folder 163)
  - Orbits - autograph manuscript notes., 1898-1899 (Box 7, Folder 164)
  - Orbits: National Academy - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - Orbits: Astronomical Miscellany - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 166)
  - Orbits: Theory of Elliptic Motion - autograph manuscript notes., 1882 (Box 7, Folder 167)
  - Orbits: Method of 3 Distances with three additional terms - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 168)
  - Orbits: W. Ames Ceres - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 169)
  - Orbits: Elliptic Motion with Differentiation of Elements - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 170)
  - Orbits: Rough Estimate of Perturbations - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 171)
  - Orbits: First Stages in the Determination of Orbits - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 172)
  - Orbits: 2 Additional Terms - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 173)
  - Orbits: Parabolic Orbits Determined by Equation in 3 Distances - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 174)
  - Orbits: Ceres III Hypo and Residuals, Ceres Theoria Motus - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - Orbits: Correction of Formulae - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 176)
  - Orbits: Comet 1892a, Reference Formula and Derivations - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 177)
  - Orbits: Parameter and Areas, Moore's Problem for Hyperbola's Elements - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Orbits: Method of three distances - autograph manuscript notes., 1886 (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - Orbits: Comets 1882 - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 180)
  - Orbits: Perturbations - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - Orbits: Solution of Fundamental Equations - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - Orbits: Comet Klinkertues, Gould - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - Orbits: Ames on Ceres - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Orbits: Swift's Comet - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - Orbits: Theory of Ellipses: Two Tangents, Calculations - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 186)
  - Orbits: Fundamental Formula for Orbits - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 187)
  - Orbits: Comet 1892a Elliptic Orbit - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 188)
  - Orbits: Memior on Orbits - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - Orbits: Ellipse from 3 Positions, Heliometer observations - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - Orbits: Heliometer - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 191)
  - Orbits: Residuals of Hyp. II - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 192)
  - Orbits: Perturbations by Differences - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 193)
  - Orbits: Swift's Comet, Memoir Ceres Correction - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 194)
  - Orbits: Pallas Theoria Motus - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 195)
  - Orbits: Theory of Improved Fundamental Equation in Orbits - autograph manuscript notes., 1889 (Box 8, Folder 196)
  - Orbits: Determination of Orbits: Method of 3 Heliocentric Distances - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 197)
  - Orbits: N1, N2, N3, Method of 3 Distances with One Additional Term - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 198)
  - Orbits: Parabola: Search for Additional Terms in Fundamental Equations - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 199)
  - Orbits: Calculations on Determination of Orbits - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 200)
  - Orbits: Determination of Orbits - Formulae - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - Orbits: Parabolic Motion - autograph manuscript notes., 1891 (Box 8, Folder 202)
  - Orbits: Comet 1892a - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - Orbits: Ceres: Control of Numbers in Memior - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 204)
  - Orbits: Unidentified leaves - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 8, Folder 205)
  - Electromagnetic Theory of Light - list of folders, undated (Box 9, Folder 206)
  - Electromagnetic Theory of Light - autograph manuscript notes, 1887; 3 (Box 9, Folder 207-209)
  - Vector Analysis - autograph manuscript notes for lectures., 1879-1902 (Box 10, Folder 210)
  - Vector Analysis: Mimeographed course synopsis - autograph manuscript notes., undated; 4 (Box 10, Folder 211-214)
  - Electricity and Magnetism - autograph manuscript notes., 1885-1900; 4 (Box 10, Folder 215-218)
  - Statistical Mechanics: autograph manuscript notes for book., undated (Box 11, Folder 219)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Statistical Equilibrium cases - autograph manuscript notes for book, undated (Box 11, Folder 220)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Chapter VIII, Chapter XIV - autograph manuscript notes for book., undated (Box 11, Folder 221)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Thermodynamics of Ether (Queries) - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 222)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Equilibrium in Sub-continus - autograph manuscript notes., 1894 (Box 11, Folder 223)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Examples of Intermolecular Action - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 224)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Statistical Mechanics Generalities - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 225)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Vq from V when N is Odd - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 226)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Psi and Th as Force Functions - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 227)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Examples of Ideal Gases - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 228)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Units and Zeros (Dimensions) - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 229)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Micro: Notes on Microcanonical Distribution - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 230)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Coexistant Phases and Unstable States - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 231)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Chapter XII, Tendencies, etc. - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 232)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Chapter XV, Systems of Molecules - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 233)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Empty folder covers, undated (Box 11, Folder 234)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Miscellaneous loose sheets on various topics, undated (Box 11, Folder 235)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Canonical Averages - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 236)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Molecular Mechanics and Thermodynamics - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 237)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Chapter V (old) i.e. Residuum of V, VI, and VII - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 238)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Chapter III - autograph manuscript notes for book., undated (Box 11, Folder 239)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Chapter IV - autograph manuscript notes for book., undated (Box 11, Folder 240)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Empty folder covers, undated (Box 11, Folder 241)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Loose sheets on various topics - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 242)
  - Statistical Mechanics: Chapter V, Chapter XI: Maximum and Minimum Properties - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 11, Folder 243)
  - Statistical Mechanics: unidentified leaf., undated (Box 11, Folder 244)
  - Dynamics - autograph manuscript notes., undated (Box 12, Folder 245)
  - Bibliographies - autograph manuscript notes., 1878 (Box 12, Folder 246)
  - Multiple Algebra for Dynamics - autograph manuscript notes., 1896 (Box 12, Folder 247)
  - Photostats of 2 autograph letters, signed, from Lynde Wheeler regarding Gibbs' Multiple Algebra for Dynamics, 1957 November 11 and 22 (Box 12, Folder 248)
  - The Last Unpublished Notes of J. Willard Gibbs - booklet by Edwin B. Wilson, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 249)
  - Lynde Wheeler's manuscript notes from Multiple Algebra for Dynamics., 1957 (Box 12, Folder 250)
  - Microfilm of "Gibbs's notes" requested by Lynde P. Wheeler from Yale University Library Rare Book Room, undated (Box 12, Folder 250a)
  - Photostats of a portion of Gibbs' notes on Multiple Algebra for Dynamics., undated (Box 12, Folder 251)
  - Rayleigh on Sound - autograph manuscript notes on J. W. S. Rayleigh's Theory of Sound., undated (Box 12, Folder 252)
  - Abstract for "Konigsberger's Repertorium" - autograph manuscript notes., 1879 (Box 12, Folder 253)
  - Elementary Principles in Statistical Mechanics - autograph manuscript notes., undated; 3 (Box 13, Folder 254-256)
  - Elementary Principles in Statistical Mechanics - proof sheets., undated; 3 (Box 13, Folder 257-259)
  - Unidentified scientific papers in autograph manuscript., undated (Box 13, Folder 260)
  - List of Awards, Honors, Memberships, etc., undated (Box 14, Folder 261)
  - Awards, Honors, Memberships in Learned Societies, etc., 1879-1902; 3 (Box 14, Folder 262-264)
  - Certificate appointing Gibbs to the National Conference of Electricians, from President Chester Arthur., 1884 July 22 (Box 14, Folder 265)
  - Honorary degress, Memberships in Learned Societies, etc., 1884 (Box 14, Folder 266)
  - Certificate of Admission to Yale College, 1854 July (Box 14, Folder 267)
  - Notes on Death, 1904 May (Box 14, Folder 268)
  - Personal Recollections and Impressions of J. Willard Gibbs by His Neice, Nephews, and Certain of His Pupils - bound volume., 1947 (Box 14, Folder 269)
    Deposited in the Yale University Library by Lynde P. Wheeler and Ralph G. Van Name, 1947 October 15
  - Programs and other papers relating to Gibbs' continental studies., undated (Box 14, Folder 270)
  - Honors, Awards, and Memberships, 1880-1902 (Box 15 (Oversize))
- Class Notes by George P. Starkweather, 1892-1897; Series III; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - Manuscript notebook of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Maxwell's Electricity and Magnetism, Volume I., 1895-1896 (Box 16, Folder 271)
  - Manuscript notebook of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Maxwell's Electricity and Magnetism, Volume II., 1895-1896 (Box 16, Folder 272)
  - Manuscript notebook of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Maxwell's Electricity and Magnetism, Volume III., 1895-1896 (Box 16, Folder 273)
  - Manuscript notebook of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Thermodynamics, Volume I., 1893-1894 (Box 16, Folder 274)
  - Manuscript notebook of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Thermodynamics, Volume II., 1893-1894 (Box 16, Folder 275)
  - Manuscript notebook of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Thermodynamics, Volume III., 1893-1894 (Box 16, Folder 276)
  - Manuscript notebook of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Electromagnetic Theory of Light, Volume I., 1892-1893, 1896-1897 (Box 17, Folder 277)
  - Manuscript notebook of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Electromagnetic Theory of Light, Volume II., 1892-1893 (Box 17, Folder 278)
  - Manuscript notebook of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Electromagnetic Theory of Light, Volume II., 1892-1893, 1896-1897 (Box 17, Folder 279)
  - Manuscript notebooks of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Elliptic and Parabolic Motions and Computation of Orbits, Volumes I and II., undated (Box 17, Folder 280)
  - Manuscript notebooks of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Vector Applications, Volumes I and II., 1894-1895 (Box 17, Folder 281)
  - Manuscript notebooks of lecture notes taken by George P. Starkweather on Dynamics and Thermodynamics, Volumes I and II., 1894-1895 (Box 17, Folder 282)
- Photographs and Illustrations, 1860-1903; Series IV; 1.13
  - Architectural plans of Yale College, undated (Box 18, Folder 283)
  - Photographs of Hopkins Grammar School, 1860s (Box 18, Folder 284)
  - Photographs of a model of the thermodynamic surface of water, undated (Box 18, Folder 285)
  - Photographic portrait of J. Willard Gibbs by Filley(?), New Haven., undated (Box 18, Folder 286)
  - Photographic portrait of J. Willard Gibbs by Pach Bros., New York., undated (Box 18, Folder 287)
  - Photographic portrait of J. Willard Gibbs by Pach Bros., New York., undated (Box 18, Folder 288)
  - Photographic portrait of J. Willard Gibbs by Wilhelm Engelmann, Leipzig., 1895? (Box 18, Folder 289)
  - Draft Gear Illustration, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 290)
  - Assorted negatives, undated (Box 18, Folder 291)
  - Photographic portraits of Gibbs as a young man, Gibbs as an adult, and Mary Anna Van Clare Gibbs., undated (Box 18, Folder 292)
  - 71 High Street, New Haven, home of J. Willard Gibbs (later 121 High Street)., undated (Box 18, Folder 293)
  - Portraits of Gibbs, and correspondence between Ruth Adams and Ralph Van Name., 1957 (Box 18, Folder 294)
  - Portraits of Gibbs, undated (Box 19 (Oversize))
- Letter by and to J. Willard Gibbs (1790-1861), 1811-1860; Series V; 0.83
  Other Finding Aids
  Organized into two subseries: Letters by J. Willard Gibbs and Letters to J. Willard Gibbs
  - Letters by J. Willard Gibbs
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Messrs. Baldwin and Forbes. New Haven., 1828 March 24 (Box 20, Folder 295)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Reverand E. C. Bridgman. New Haven., 1845 October 15 (Box 20, Folder 296)
    - Copy of a letter, in Mrs. Gibbs' hand, to James Carnahan. New Haven., 1853 July 11 (Box 20, Folder 297)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Professor Jeremiah Day, accompanied by a manuscript confession of faith. Salem., 1811 November 7, 1811 December 2 (Box 20, Folder 298)
    - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Joseph Henry. New Haven., 1849 November 10, 1852 November 27 (Box 20, Folder 299)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Samuel J. Hitchcock. Salem., 1820 July 18 (Box 20, Folder 300)
    - Certificate, signed, for William A. Macy. New Haven., 1845 October 15 (Box 20, Folder 301)
    - 2 autograph letters, signed, to J. Robert Morrison. New Haven., 1843 June 26 and September 5 (Box 20, Folder 302)
    - Minutes concerning a teacher for the Morrison Education Society., 1843 May 16 (Box 20, Folder 303)
    - Copy of an autograph letter, signed, to the Trustees of Morrison Education Society. New Haven., 1844 October 18 (Box 20, Folder 304)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to the Trustees of the Morrison Education Society. New Haven., 1845 October 15 (Box 20, Folder 305)
    - Certificate, signed, for Oscar Smith. New Haven., 1858 July 24 (Box 20, Folder 306)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Increase N. Tarbox. New Haven., 1851 July 14 (Box 20, Folder 307)
  - Letters to J. Willard Gibbs
    - List of Correspondence (Box 20, Folder 308)
    - Adamson, James - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Capetown, South Africa., 1850 July 29 (Box 20, Folder 309)
    - Adler, George J. (1821-1868) - 3 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1858 September 27, 1860 July 26 and October 4 (Box 20, Folder 310)
    - Appleton, D. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1858 December 16 (Box 20, Folder 311)
    - Arnoux, William Henry - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1860 February 21 (Box 20, Folder 312)
    - Ball, Dyer - Printed circular on "Chinese Chistomathy" with manuscript note to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Macao, [China]., 1842 January 15 (Box 20, Folder 313)
    - Barnard, Henry - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Hartford., 1856 November 15 (Box 20, Folder 314)
    - Barnes, Jona[than] E. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Middletown., 1858 December 6 (Box 20, Folder 315)
    - Bartlett, S. F. - Autograph letter, signed, to Reverand Chauncey Goodrich. Lyon, Connecticut., 1843 November 20 (Box 20, Folder 316)
    - Beecher, William Henry - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). North Brookfield, Massachusetts., 1859 February 22 (Box 20, Folder 317)
    - Blodget, Henry (1825-1903) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Waterville, Maine., 1853 October 25 (Box 20, Folder 318)
    - Bonney, Samuel W. - 4 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York and Hong Kong., 1844 October 3, 19, and 29, 1845 April 2 (Box 20, Folder 319)
    - Bradley, Charles William (1807-1865) - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New Haven and Singapore., 1852 July 15, 1855 April 13 (Box 20, Folder 320)
    - Brewer, Josiah (1796-1872) - 3 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Wethersfield, Connecticut; Hartford; and New Haven., 1839 July 11, 1843 November 11, 1844 August 9 (Box 20, Folder 321)
    - Bridgeman, Elijah Coleman (1801-1861) - 10 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Various places., 1837-1845 (Box 20, Folder 322)
    - Brigham, J. C. - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1841 May 12, 1858 August 4 (Box 20, Folder 323)
    - Brown, D. F. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Xenia Greene County, Ohio., 1858 June 1 (Box 20, Folder 324)
    - Brown, Samuel Robbins (1810-1880) - 4 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Macao and Hong Kong., 1839 September 13 and November 4, 1842 April 1, 1844 October 22 (Box 20, Folder 325)